The first-class mage exam will now begin.
You will be tested as parties.
The 57 exam-takers will split into teams
of three for the first test.
See? I knew you could do it.
You think so?
Lawine is rough, but she
pulls me along with her.
Our first battle against a dragon is tomorrow.
Are you scared, Eisen?
You're shaking.
Yeah.
I see. In that case...
Wait, what? You're scared?
Yeah.
I see. I'm scared, too.
What kind of conversation is this?
I thought I'd copy other adventurers
and inspire you, but...
I'm sorry. It doesn't seem to have worked.
No. Thanks to you, I'm no longer tense.
Himmel, just be yourself.
I'm sure this sort of thing
differs from party to party.
You're right.
I see. It really does differ
from party to party.
We finally caught a Stille.
Now we don't have to worry.
Why are you so relaxed?
The hard part's still to come.
We have to keep our Stille
from being stolen by other parties.
It's time to fight other mages.
Let's review what we learned
from observing the Stille.
First, like Frieren said, those birds
fly faster than the speed of sound.
We could never catch up to it at that speed.
Furthermore, they're as tough as dragons.
Common attack spells have no effect,
and they break free of most restraints.
On top of that, they're sensitive to mana.
Even when we suppress our mana to
approach one, it quickly flies away.
The biggest problem of all is because the
Stille themselves have practically no mana,
we can't find them using mana detection.
Because of that, we have
no idea where they are now.
We don't know how many there are either.
The only ones we ever spotted were
those three yesterday morning.
They're probably being cautious because
the test-takers are searching for them.
Worst case, they might
never show themselves again.
And even if we do find one,
we have no idea how to catch it.
Don't worry about that.
Last night I experimented with a spell
that might be useful for catching a Stille.
I remember you going out.
What kind of spell is it?
I already showed you, Kanne.
A spell that captures a bird.
It's a folk spell developed by
a tribe of hunters during an era
when mages and magic were far more common.
Come to think of it, you did use
a spell to restrain that creature.
But wasn't that a monster and not a bird?
It's folk magic, after all.
It appears it can be used to capture
anything that broadly resembles a bird.
It's a powerful binding spell.
I think it'll probably work on the Stille.
Why didn't you say so earlier?
We could've caught one yesterday
if we'd used that.
Actually, we couldn't have.
That spell's range is 50 centimeters.
You have to get that close to use it.
Fifty centimeters?
How close have we gotten so far?
Three meters was the closest.
Not only that, but they noticed us
by the time we got within 20 meters of them.
So we're one step short
of meeting the requirements.
That's one huge step.
Just to confirm, it's difficult for you two
to stop the Stille with your magic, right?
It'd probably work if we could freeze one,
but they're sensitive to mana, tough,
and resistant to freezing.
It'd probably escape before
we could fix it in place.
I bet we could easily stop one with my magic
if we had access to a ton of water.
But my magic only allows me to control water.
I can't create it out of nothing.
So I can't use it unless
there's water present,
and mana struggles to penetrate
large bodies of water.
I'd probably have to infuse it
with my mana beforehand.
I can quickly take control of even large
amounts of water if it's scattered, like rain.
But if I infused water with mana, the mana-
sensitive Stille would definitely stay away.
Stay away?
I see. They'd stay away.
This plan might work.
It's not bad, but it's risky.
We'd be picking a fight
with all the other teams.
But I doubt we'll catch one otherwise.
Are you scared, Lawine?
Ow, ow, ow! You're gonna rip them off!
Fine.
Let's do this.
For now, let's hide until the test is over.
What? That's no fun.
We're mages. We should fight openly.
Mages also avoid unnecessary fighting.
But first, we should get water.
I think there was a lake
in the middle of the area.
Either way, I'm glad
we caught a Stille so quickly.
If we can remain hidden until sunset,
we'll pass the first test.
What is it?
Looks like it won't be that easy.
I thought this was a road,
but it's actually a dry riverbed.
Not only that, but I saw similar
terrain in a few other places.
Isn't there a barrier around the testing area?
Yeah. That's standard for tests.
They're powerful physical barriers
that keep out even specks of dust.
Do they block water, too?
Oh.
Judging by the dryness,
the barrier was erected over a week ago.
Then most of the water will have collected
in the lake in the middle of the valley.
Since the test-takers are living creatures,
we need some amount of water to stay active.
That doesn't guarantee test-takers
would gather around the lake.
You're right.
We can carry water with us.
But the Stille, which are
also living creatures, cannot.
I see. And those who have realized that
will be waiting around the lake,
the largest body of water in the area.
Okay, I've made my decision.
We'll give up on finding water.
That'll be tough. I'm already parched.
I'm sure we can find a small pond.
Is that sanitary?
Perhaps if we boil it.
What a pain in the ass.
I was shooting to kill.
You're quick enough to react to that?
Well, whatever.
Leave the cage with the Stille.
And if we refuse?
Then there's no need for words.
The lake is that way.
They froze the lake.
Seriously? What are they doing?
This isn't funny.
That's the mana of one of
the 2nd party's members.
What are they thinking?
Are they trying to antagonize
all the other parties?
What are you doing?
Hurry up and melt it!
Denken, what should we do?
It's a waste of time and effort.
There's no point in melting it now.
After that showy display of magic,
the Stille won't come near this lake again.
We'll steal our Stille from the 2nd party.
If they went this wild,
they must have a plan to catch one.
Ms. Frieren, what are you doing?
Let's scatter for now.
We have to melt the frozen lake quickly!
Those fools.
Using that much magic to melt the ice
will make the lake truly useless.
The Stille won't come near here again.
Let's go.
Yeah.
That way!
Those who realized that are searching
for other watering holes,
but their mana detection is inadequate.
They won't be able to handle airborne threats.
They're inexperienced.
Apparently the 2nd party froze the lake.
Are they trying to ruin the test?
Ruin it? No.
The 2nd party has a well-laid plan.
Until we unravel it, we won't get anywhere.
Monsters got them.
They're already dead.
Let's go.
Sir, let's at least take them down.
You can see them, can't you?
They're circling above.
Not just one or two of them either.
There's magic on those corpses.
They'll detect you
if you try to take them down.
Geisel. That's how they lure
and hunt their next prey.
This party fell for their trap
and got themselves killed.
It's strange that they chose
to administer the test in an area
inhabited by monsters like these.
It's like they think nothing
of the test-takers dying.
Laufen, this is your first time
taking the first-class exam, isn't it?
Their reasoning is incredibly simple.
Anyone who would die here is
unqualified to be a first-class mage.
The Continental Magic Association
is very mindful of maintaining
the quality of first-class mages.
There are those who still dream
of the powerful and noble mages
who fought the Demon King's forces.
Damn their outdated ideas.
I'm surprised, Denken.
I thought you'd be on their side.
The quality of a mage is irrelevant.
First-class mages need only
be symbols of power.
No matter how powerful you are,
unless you can control people's hearts,
you're as good as powerless.
I've seen countless mages
far more skilled than myself
fall from power and be persecuted.
Great power is feared,
and rule by fear doesn't last long.
Besides, magic isn't a noble thing.
I see. So someone as weak as you
is perfect for the job.
Watch your tongue, boy.
I could beat you with my eyes closed.
We've had no luck detecting the 2nd party.
They're concealing their mana and hiding.
This place, too. All the watering holes
we've seen are the same.
It's faint, but there's mana in the water.
I don't sense anything.
Do you?
No. Is it the 2nd party?
I doubt even the person
who cast it could detect it.
There's that little in it.
But a Stille could sense it.
They won't come near this water again.
What's the point of doing this?
I see. There's a watering hole somewhere
that doesn't contain mana.
And that's where the 2nd party will be.
How will we find it?
I'm going to rest a bit.
Denken.
The testing area is enormous.
It'd be impossible to find a mage
who truly doesn't want to be found.
We'll wait.
They'll show us where they are eventually.
I infused every lake and pond
I could find with mana.
It's possible there are bodies of water
we don't know about, though.
Just limiting the watering holes
the Stille can use is enough.
I'll wait here for a Stille.
Seriously? It's possible to completely
suppress your mana?
Not completely.
When I move, I release a little mana. See?
I can't sense it.
We'll stand watch.
Don't hold us back.
Shut up.
If it'd just rain,
I could be useful in a fight.
But the barrier would deflect all of it.
Frieren, did you do it?
It was worth picking a fight
with the other parties.
Now we'll pass the first test.
No.
Found them.
So they used magic after all.
Not even the most skilled mage
can conceal that moment.
Someone's detected us.
We should get away from here.
Looks like it's too late to run.
Jubelade.
Doragate.
It's like a cannon.
She backed off again.
Her technique is refined
and shows no openings, but it's old.
It's like fighting against my grandfather.
Ordinary offensive magic and defensive magic.
You only use basic spells.
Are you playing things close to the chest?
I was taught to only use
basic spells in combat.
That's your master's philosophy, then?
Yes. She said it's enough
to defeat mages of this era.
Oh, yeah?
Again. What is this feeling of wrongness?
It's like I'm fighting an experienced mage.
You're going to struggle.
If you fought Wirbel with your technique,
you'd be dead by now.
That doesn't make sense.
You're the strongest one here, aren't you?
Wirbel is the captain of the
Northern Magic Corps that fought
against the remnants
of the Demon King's forces.
He has far more experience in battle.
His magic is devoid of character.
It's underhanded,
for the sole purpose of winning.
The girl fighting Wirbel now
will probably be killed.
Is that so?
What hells have you seen?
I'll take your head off.
I'll crush her.
He's strong.
Interesting. Try me.
This is impressive.
What's this sound?
You old fart.
I've always killed everyone I had to.